JOHN HEHER

Full-stack Web Developer

Experienced web developer with a focus on the front-end. With over a decade of extensive and quality work, I'm ready to help out wherever needed. I have worked with big companies and small startups, so I'm adaptable to any environment. Most of my front-end work has been using React with TypeScript/JavaScript and a back-end built with Node, Express, and PostgreSQL.

1-512-656-9798 johnheher@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/johnheher github.com/heher johnheher.com

EXPERIENCE

Sabbatical

Earth (11/2022 - 08/2023)

- Decided to put all my stuff in storage and solo travel. The goal was to go to every Olympic city I could but also to see as many overall cities and countries as possible along the way. Ended up going to 29 countries.
- Whether having to figure a new way across Norway/Sweden during an Oslo blackout, or battling for the few busses to Bologna during an historic Italian flood, was able to adapt to any unforeseen circumstance.
- Traveling on savings and out of one backpack, being resourceful was absolutely necessary to stretch what I had on me to do everything from ski in Bosnia to run a half marathon in New Zealand.
- While freeing, having no one else with me, I had to be persistent no matter how hungry, tired, or sick I was at the time.

Senior Web Developer

Disney+, Remote (03/2022 - 11/2022)

- · Technologies: React, TypeScript, JavaScript, Jest
- Led project for a new onboarding flow for new users which has ultimately become the first screen millions of users see around the world when signing up for Disney+.
- Adapted functionality and design for multiple world regions and languages, combining back-end systems to create a seamless front-end product.
- Translated legacy Disney+ code to modern styling and frameworks, which consisted mostly of rewriting React class components written in JavaScript to functional React written in TypeScript.

Senior Web Developer

Palo Alto Networks, Remote (03/2021 - 03/2022)

- Technologies: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Storybook, Ant Design
- Revamped the dashboard within the company's support portal, boosting performance while adding features
 to speed up customer support times and reduce the amount of support calls.
- Rewrote bloated components for efficiency and readability while consolidating common styling and components into a new Storybook library for consistent design across dev teams.
- Restyled Ant Design components using in-house designs to achieve custom functionality with a consistent look.

Director, Front-end development

PHLUR, Austin, TX (11/2016 - 02/2020)

- Technologies: React, JavaScript, GraphQL, Ruby, HTML, CSS, Storybook
- Single-handedly architected, designed, and coded all front-end systems within the company.
- Ultimately took a chaotic mix of jQuery within a Rails app and broke it out into its own system with React, GraphQL, and common styling.
- Continued to add new functionality/products/categories including moving payment processors in the middle
 of a new product launch.
- Worked with leadership on a daily basis to adapt marketing campaigns, review KPIs and site performance, and discuss anything else needed to grow the company. This resulted in revenue increasing fivefold during my time at Phlur.

EXPERIENCE CONT.

Presentation Layer Engineer

Razorfish, Austin, TX (09/2014 - 04/2016)

- · Technologies: Jade, JavaScript, CoffeeScript, Sass, jQuery, Node
- Helped lead the overhaul of a banking system for Citibank, coordinating with professionals across the globe.
- Worked within multiple teams to create a unified customer portal for Citi that could be white-labeled with the styling of their partners to feel like a custom experience.
- Took it upon myself to create a unified codebase to align custom styling and functionality with Fortune 500 partners.
- Realizing the dev teams were repeating CSS code, I worked with the lead designer to create a Sass plugin system that could be used to immensely cut down on the time styling a partner page.

Lead Front-end Developer

Greenling, Austin, TX (03/2013 - 09/2014)

- · Technologies: jQuery, CoffeeScript, JavaScript, Ruby, Sass
- Spearheaded a major rebrand, collaborating with designers to deliver a responsive and efficient user experience.
- Was hired to architect and develop all aspects of the visual and functional redesign of the e-commerce site that also included all changes to marketing and invoice emails.

Senior Web Developer

Traction, San Francisco, CA (10/2011 - 07/2012)

- · Technologies: Ruby, YAML, JavaScript, Photoshop
- Coded and QA-tested marketing emails for Apple ensuring consistency across various devices and browsers.
- Used and developed an in-house Ruby templating system to create emails off Photoshop designs that would be uploaded and sent through Apple's system.

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Business Administration (Information Technology & E-Commerce) University of Denver, 2010

SKILLS

Front-end

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, TypeScript, Email templates, ADA compliance

Back-end

Node, Ruby on Rails, Docker

Testing

Jest, Testing Library, Playwright

Databases

GraphQL, PostgreSQL, SQL

Design Tools

Photoshop, Figma, Sketch, Storybook

PERSONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Slapped by Saint/Pope John Paul II.
- Successfully crewed and maintained stern lines in 1,000+ mile journey down the Intracoastal Waterway.
- · Ongoing multi-decade reign as family Turkey Trot champion.